JESSICA CLAIRE

- resumesample@example
- (555) 432-1000,
- Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

- **?**:
- 8
- **€**

SUMMARY

Flexible accountant who adapts seamlessly to constantly evolving accounting processes and technology. Seasoned staff accountant with ten year background in accounting. Core competencies include detailed oriented, organized, and as well as excellent communication and time management skills. Handles tasks with accuracy and efficiency. Passionate and motivated, with a drive for excellence.

HIGHLIGHTS

Microsoft Excel (v-lookups, ma pivot tables), Microsoft Power Microsoft Access, Microsoft Wo Microsoft Outlook, JD Edwards 400. Microsoft Accounting Offi Image Freeway, QuickBooks, S LX, SAGE

EDUCATION

Keller Graduate School of Management Decatur, GA • 2008 – –

Master of Business

Administration: Accounting -GPA: 3.67 Accounting GPA: 3.67

DeVry University Decatur, GA • 2006 â€" â€"

Bachelor of Science: Technical Management Accounting - GPA: GPA: 3.66 Cum Laude, and Dean's List Technical Management Accounting GPA: 3.66 Cum Laude, and Dean's

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

EXPERIENCE

Aristotle Capital Management, Llc - Accountant

Newport Beach, CA, • • 09/2014 - Current

- Manage Construction in Progress Accounts, depreciation, additions, transfers, & dispositions of tangible and intangible assets.
- Tracked all capital spending against approved capital requests.
- Reconcile the fixed assets subsidiary ledger and generate monthly ad hoc reports to effectively complete the monthly roll forward.
- Record and maintain capital leases.
- Create and monitor a system of controls, procedures, and forms for the recordation of fixed assets.
- Assist with full cycle accounting and financial reporting for month end close Prepare multiple balance sheet reconciliations.
- · Perform research and analyses to determine trends, estimates, and significant changes for various P&L accounts.
- Manage property tax statements and update monthly accruals.
- Collaborate and maintain strong working relationships with the field as well as corporate finance and other corporate departments.
- · Provide support, research, analysis, and information reporting as needed to the Regional Finance Directors, Plant Controllers, Operations Management, and Corporate Finance.
- Assist with interim & annual audit.
- · Work on special projects and prepare ad hoc reports and analysis as needed.

Alliant Group - Senior Staff Accountant Houston, TX, • • 01/2013 - 10/2014

- Perform a significant role in month-end close including preparation of production reports, journal entries and account reconciliations.
- Analyze financial transactions and assist in the preparation of balance sheets, P&L's and other financial reports.
- Ensure that transactions are coded accurately and financial reporting integrity is maintained.
- Review & analyze monthly product cost as well as publish and analyze monthly
- actual reports.
- Manage Construction in Process Accounts, fixed assets, depreciation, additions, transfers, & dispositions of fixed and intangible assets.
- Conduct annual physical inventory for fixed assets for manufacturing plants, distribution centers & galleries.
- Compose Quarterly Consolidated Financial Statements for parent company.
- Generate Intercompany Foreign Currency Financial Statements.
- Observe and reconcile physical inventory.
- Calculate year-end raw materials inventory for manufacturing facilities.
- Compile analysis of corporate financial data to provide management with internal reports.
- Assist controller with interim & annual audit.
- Provide consequential analysis and support, ad hoc requests, projects and other duties assigned by the Director or VP of Finance.
- Review and explain variances to budget/forecast for production on a monthly, quarterly, and annual basis.

Vista Equity Partners - Staff Accountant

Morrisville, NC, • • 02/2016 - 12/2012

- Prepare journal entries for expense allocations, accruals, corrections &
- Manage master data in ERP system for all new inventory items.
- · Prepare wire transfers for processing of inter-company payments.
- Process monthly sales commissions and commission Transfers.
- Prepare the budget forecast for annual capital budget for all construction in process accounts.
- · Prepare bank account reconciliations.
- Prepared, examined, or analyzed accounting records, financial statements, or other financial reports to assess accuracy, completeness, and conformance to reporting and procedural standards.
- Developed, maintained, and analyzed budgets, preparing periodic reports that compare budgeted costs to actual costs.

Associated Credit Union - General Ledger Specialist

City, STATE, • • 05/2016 - 02/2016

- Post daily journal entries to general ledger.
- Reconciled fixed asset accounts and other balance sheet accounts.
- Reconciled teller daily balance sheets and prepares summary worksheet Prepared weekly FR2900 Regulation D Federal Reserve Requirement Report.
- Assisted in the month-end close and year-end close Analyze and correct all bank account reconciliations Execute wire transfers Assist with interim & annual audit.
- · Perform other job-related duties and special projects.

SKILLS

account reconciliations, Accounting, accruals, ad, AS 400, balance sheet, balance sheets, budgets, budget, controller, Corporate Finance, ERP, Finance, financial, financial reports, financial reporting, Financial Statements, fixed assets, forms, general ledger, Image, inventory, JD Edwards, ledger, Director, macros, materials, Microsoft Access, Microsoft Excel, Office, Microsoft Outlook, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Word, month end close, Operations Management, pivot tables, Progress, QuickBooks, reporting, Requirement, research, SAGE FAS, sales, SAP, tax, year-end